## Guillermo Peralta Scura

### **Senior Frontend Engineer**

Seasoned and meticulous Senior Frontend Engineer with over 7 years of experience in software engineering. Specializes in crafting highly accessible websites with optimized initial page rendering. Proven capability to work efficiently in team environments and solve complex problems. Committed to delivering high-quality results and driving innovation in frontend development.

# Barcelona, Spain P+595982742811 D gperaltascura@gmail.com /voluntadpear /guillermo-peralta-scura @voluntadpear https://scura.dev

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**PSPDFKit GmbH,** Vienna, Austria (Remote) — *Senior Web Engineer* SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Directed the development and enhancement of several critical features for the <u>PSPDFKit for Web PDF editor</u>, leveraging technologies like React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, React Testing Library, and Playwright. Demonstrating deep expertise in DOM manipulation and computer graphics concepts.
- Orchestrated the creation of <u>the new SDK demo site</u> utilizing Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Playwright, and Storybook.
   Successfully built and presented a proof-of-concept that significantly contributed to the signing of a major deal with a customer, and later became the <u>official SharePoint offering</u>.
- Provided direct support to customers via email and calls, troubleshooting their integrations and guiding them through our product offerings.
- Mentored new hires and engineers across teams, fostering a culture of knowledge sharing and mutual growth.
- Authored several technical blog posts, enhancing the company's industry credibility and client engagement. [1] [2] [3]

### **Sulvo,** Las Vegas, NV (Remote) — Web developer

APRIL 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Championed the progressive migration of the main application from Meteor Blaze to Vue, and initiated the use of Jest for unit and integration testing, boosting application performance and test coverage.
- Implemented a modernized web development toolkit using
   Webpack and Jest, enhancing UX and developer productivity.
- Worked closely with the UI designer to craft compelling user interactions, increasing user engagement and satisfaction.

# **Codium,** Asunción, Paraguay — *Web and mobile developer*JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2018

 Played a key role in <u>PeerDoc</u>, an open-source collaborative document editor, using Vue for the frontend and Meteor for the backend.

### **SKILLS**

### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Elixir

### Frameworks/Libraries

React, Next.js, Redux, Jest, React Testing Library, Playwright, Vue, Qwik, Express, Apollo, AWS Lambda

### **Databases**

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

### **EDUCATION**

National University of Asunción, Asunción, Paraguay — Computer Engineering 2012 - 2019

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (native), English (advanced)

### **PROJECTS**

### ChatGOV — <u>Live version</u>

Developed an AI-powered assistant capable of answering questions based on Paraguayan laws.

### **Qwik-transition** — <u>Source</u> <u>Code on GitHub</u>

Custom hook for adding smooth CSS transitions to Qwik components.